{
    "American History": [
        {
            "value": 100,
            "question": "On July 20, 1969, these two astronaughts walked on the moon",
            "answer": "Neil Armstron and Buzz Aldrin"
        },
        {
            "value": 200,
            "question": "This person was the second US president",
            "answer": "John Adams"
        },
        {
            "value": 400,
            "question": "The 18th Amendment also called the Volstead act, had this effect.",
            "answer": "what is a ban on manufacturing, sale, and transportation of alcohol"
        },
        {
            "value": 300,
            "question": "With this invention, Eli Whitney revolutionized the US Economy",
            "answer": "The Cotton Gin or Automated Rife production"
        },
        {
            "value": 500,
            "question": "This Socialist run unsuccessfully for president 5 times, with one attempt from jail",
            "answer": "Who is Eugene V. Deps"
        }
    ],
    "World History": [
        {
            "value": 100,
            "question": "The assassination of this person instigated the first world war",
            "answer": "Arch-Duke Franz Ferdinand"
        },
        {
            "value": 200,
            "question": "Nicolaus Copernicus is most famous for this theory",
            "answer": "Heliocentrism, The sun being the centre of the solar system"
        },
        {
            "value": 300,
            "question": "Allied forces landed on several beaches on June 6th, 1944, which were given these code names",
            "answer": "Utah, Omaha, Gold, Juno and Sword"
        },
        {
            "value": 400,
            "question": "The after the French revoltuion, the new French goverment replacted Catholicism with this state sponsered religion",
            "answer": "The Cult of Reason (Culte de la Raison)"
        },
        {
            "value": 500,
            "question": "During the Russian Revolution, Vladimir  Lenin promised his revolutionaries these three things",
            "answer": "What are Land, Bread, and Peace"
        }

    ],
    "Science": [
        {
            "value": 100,
            "question": "A cell can duplicate itself after undergoing this process",
            "answer": "What is Mitosis"
        },
        {
            "value": 200,
            "question": "An atom is composed of these three subatomic particles",
            "answer": "What are Protron, Electron, and Neutron"
        },
        {
            "value": 300,
            "question": "Steel coated in this element, also called stainless Steel, resists oxidation (rust)",
            "answer": "what is Chromium"
        },
        {
            "value": 400,
            "question": "The charge an up quark has",
            "answer": "what is +2/3"
        },
        {
            "value": 500,
            "question": "This elementray particle, which as a charge of -1 and is heavier than a electron",
            "answer": "What is a muon"
        }
    ],
    "Movies": [
        {
            "value": 100,
            "question": "The second hightest grossing movie of all time, when inflation is not taken into account",
            "answer": "What is Avatar"
        },
        {
            "value": 200,
            "question": "In Star Wars, the Sith limit them selves to this number of members",
            "answer": "What is 2"
        },
        {
            "value": 300,
            "question": "The sequal to 'Blade Runner' takes place in this year.",
            "answer": "What is 2077"
        },
        {
            "value": 400,
            "question": "In  Jurassic Park, Dinosaur DNA is harvested from this source",
            "answer": "What is Mosquitos in amber"
        },
        {
            "value": 500,
            "question": "In 'V for Vendetta', V creates a personal around this historical figure",
            "answer": "Who is Guy Faux"
        }
    ],
    "US Goverment": [
        {
            "value": 100,
            "question": "A senate needs this percent of votes have a super majority  ",
            "answer": "What is 2/3 of the votes or 67 votes"
        },
        {
            "value": 200,
            "question": "The US legislative branch has this many representives",
            "answer": "What is 535: 100 senators and 435 representives"
        },
        {
            "value": 300,
            "question": "The 8th Amendment prohibts the goverment from doing what?",
            "answer": "What is imposing cruel and unusal punishment, or excessive bail"
        },
        {
            "value": 400,
            "question": "The Exectuive Branch relies on this power to enforce it's decisions",
            "answer": "What is the Power of the Sword, or military enforcment"
        },
        {
            "value": 500,
            "question": "The Legislative Branch relies on this power to enforce it's decisions",
            "answer": "What is the power of the purse, the power to spend and distrube funds from the US treasury"
        }
    ]
}